# WALEED AHMAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

■ w.ahmad1024@gmail.com

+92 320 0201300

waleedahmadg8.github.io

waleedahmadg8
wahmad1024

### **PROFILE**

I am an ambitious developer who loves to work with emerging technologies and figure out ways to create clean and efficient solutions to problems. I prefer working in a multicultural environment where I can learn and grow from my peers and apply my skill set in a better way. Its something I have experienced during my time freelancing where I worked with clients from different parts of the world, with whom I worked on projects involving thinking multiple approaches to problems. I often make sure I don't get outdated as newer technologies and innovations emerge and keep my skill set up to date. Good at multitasking, I am able to work on multiple layers at a time and make sure I play along fine as a team player.

## **WORK EXPERIENCES**

### Full Stack Developer

Strategic Systems International **2022-present** 

Working as a full-stack developer with multiple domains assigned to since I joined including frontend, backend and multiple microservices. Some of the domains I thoroughly worked on include .NET 6, Angular, React, Python, Azure CI, Azure CosmosDB, Azure API Management, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Kafka, Redis and Docker. I've been able to solve major problems during my time and have been performing great as a developer.

# Freelance Developer

**Programming Languages** 

Fiverr Level 2 Seller 2017-2022 During my undergraduate studies, I worked on Fiverr as a freelance software developer and worked on projects involving data scraping, artificial intelligence, database management et cetera. My prominent projects involved utilizing data scraping through multiple methods manipulating APIs, beautiful soup, selenium and playwright. I worked with clients from multiple regions and delivered quality codes to them earning myself a Level 2 rating with all 5-stars.

## **SKILLS**

Software Development		ASP.NET, Node.js, Flask, React, Angular, Next.js, Electron.js, Express, PostgresSQL, MongoDB, SQL, Firebase, Python eel, Basic Web Development (HTML, CSS, Sass), Docker, Redis, Apache Kafka, Elasticsearch
Data Scraping		Selenium, Beautiful Soup, Playwright, BrightData, Puppeteer, Cheerio, Jupyter
Cloud		Azure API Management, Azure Function Apps, Azure App Service, Azure Cosmos- DB, Azure DevOps
Graphic Design		Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD, Figma
	I	

Javascript, Typescript, Python, C#, C++, C, Java

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor's in Computer Science

National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences (FAST-NUCES), Lahore CGPA: 3.2/4.0

2018-2022

# F. Sc. Pre Engineering

Forman Christian College **2015-2017** 

#### RECENT PROJECTS

# BLOCKCHAIN BASED DIGITAL IDENTITY MANAGEMENT

A project aimed to provide secure method of storing and sharing digital credentials, certificates and degrees. It utilizes decentralized networks to eliminate storage of important credentials on vulnerable servers that are prone to hijacking and hacking. The blockchain architecture makes sure that the credentials are tamper-proof by generating Non-fungible tokens of the credentials. It uses smart contracts writen in clarity and is built on Stacks Blockchain, Node, is and React Framework, paired with Gaia as the cloud provider for storing secured credentials.

#### **WALL PANTHER - ANDROID**

Wall Panther is a wallpaper app which lets you view, download, and set wallpapers on both home and lock screen. The app takes wallpapers from popular mobile wallpaper subreddits on Reddit, and puts them in one single place while giving credits to the original artists of the wallpaper. It is built using Java based Android and is available on the Google Play Store.

# CONTEXT BASED LEARNING WITH OPEN AI

A research project focused around Chat-GPTs APIs utilizing a much smaller dataset of products. This AI project learns a set of products and their ratings from amazon. Chat-GPTs APIs are then used to respond on questions related to these products in this context only, rather than responding on them generally. The intended research about customizing datasets and Open AI proved to be successful.

#### DRAFTKINGS AIO DATA TOOL

A set of tools based on multiple data scraping methods, which collect and build a database of most information related to DraftKings games including NFL, MLB and NBA. The tools helps generate player rankings and other information helpful in judging player performance and other criteria required.